is a uuid V1 um sandwich attack or idor
um so that's the sandwich attack that's
what it was I should have remembered
yeah your specialty
[Music]
[Applause]
hey everyone so this week we've got a
different type of episode we had a
cancellation on the Pod and I had the
opportunity to do an episode that I was
really excited about for a really long
time which is having my wife Mariah on
the podcast now if you've listened to
critical thinking for any period of time
you know how much I mentioned her and
how much of an inspiration and help
she's been to me in my bug bounding
career so I wanted to take some time to
interview her her experiences at the
live hacking event her experiences uh
with the highs and lows of bug Bounty as
I crashed to the depth of despair over a
dupe or I'm on top of the world after I
find a crit um so uh we we did a little
interview with her and uh I think she's
really amazing I think you guys will too
um and hopefully you'll be able to take
some some tidbits out uh from our
conversation and uh apply them to your
own relationships and uh let let bug
Bounty not be uh a strainer in your
relationship but something that
amplifies it and makes it more enjoyable
so uh with that I hope you guys enjoy
this
episode all righty my love we are um we
are recording and everyone today we have
a a special episode um we had a
cancellation on the Pod so we had an
opportunity to bring on an episode that
I've really been looking forward doing
for a long time which is an episode with
my wife Mariah hi everyone I'm Mariah um
so uh let's go ahead and look at the EP
episode plan that I've got in place here
um first thing up that I that I wanted
to do was um I've got some some bug
bounty questions for you as a bug bnny
wife so let I guess let me let me let me
elaborate a little bit on what I was
thinking for this episode so um you guys
know if you've listened to the EP to the
podcast for any period of time that uh I
talk about Mariah a lot on the episodes
and um yeah she's just been a really
great support and encouragement to me uh
throughout my bug Bounty Journey so I
thought we could talk a little bit about
that and about how to encourage your
hacker and how to um I guess be an
awesome bug Bounty wife or girlfriend uh
and then I also wanted to take this
little segment in the beginning to uh
ask you some hacking questions and see
how much over the years you've absorbed
I have been to more live hacking events
that I can count more than probably most
of you will ever go to and um I've
listened to a lot of shown TOs and have
heard this one talk quite a lot about a
lot of things so I'm I'm optimistic that
you'll give me some questions I might be
able to answer s all right I think
you'll do great I think you'll do great
so let's go ahead and start it out
um first question what are the two
primary HTTP proxy softwares oh my gosh
okay HTTP proxy softwares so burp and
kaido burp and kaida that's right
correct ding ding ding one point Mariah
easy that's not even a technical
question yeah yeah okay they're coming
don't worry don't worry um H I'm not
going to go down the list in in order uh
what are the happy bug Bounty report
States like what what are the on on
hacker one is happy an acronym no no no
no no no no it's not an acronym what
what are the what are the states of a
report on hacker one that uh like triage
is that what you're talking about yeah
triage is one what what are some of the
other ones do you know any of the other
ones triaged
only uh got a dupe that's not a happy
State a happy one just that good ones
yeah can you give me any and P
tried and paid paid is not a state okay
so resed is the state resolved there you
go very nice Mariah um the the other one
is pending program review that's like
the program needs to go so it's been
triaged by the company and by hacker one
and then the company needs to go and and
review it pending program review right I
was trying to be more like program
agnostic oh okay one's not the only one
that like tries that's true that's true
yeah you're right um Okay so so what
about the sad bug Bounty States you said
one of them do for sure uh what's the
one the not applicable one not
applicable is that applicable is that
the right word not not applicable na y
um out of scope out of scope yep uh
that's not that's not a state but it is
a a uh you know a delegation they ever
just send you a thumbs down and yeah
there's there's one that starts with an
I that that I think you know I'm sure I
do I didn't hear you say it
inconceivable
inconceivable that's actually when it's
critical they give you an eye
inconceivable informative informative
yeah so like it sort of worked but it
doesn't really do anything yeah exactly
um all right let's
see in your
estimation how much time does it
normally take for a hacker to find a bug
on a new
scope for a hacker to find a bug I'm
sure it it's very it does it does that's
well we won't try to generalize it we'll
say for you and my estimation for you
okay it
takes about a week to
find 15 bugs a week to find 15 bugs so
you spend like three days not finding
any bugs whining about it and around day
four founds like seven he's like oh
never mind and then the rest of the week
he just stop find some study from there
accurate accurate yeah I think I think
that first part with three days with no
bugs and then the Title Wave I think
that's very accurate okay
um I'm not sure if I've talked to you
about this level of nuance but let me
ask you this okay so you know there's
CVSs right that's how we we rate the
vulnerabilities oh I know the CVSs
um there's a a metric in CVSs called
required okay and the values for that
metric are none low and high right so if
you find a bug on easy on an application
that is self- sign up right you can go
and and sign up nobody has to approve
anything anything like that what is the
value for the privilege required
metric if you have to be if you have to
sign up it should be
low no no Mariah you have you have
committed the fatal error um it's none
it's none yeah well we like to think
it's none for any of you program
managers listening out there this is not
an endorsement just because she says
that doesn't mean I'm going to accept it
have to be a user that means it's isn't
that by definition yeah but but
privilege required
so
the don't don't give me that look don't
give me that look the
um the attack starts
from where you know you can Define from
where the attack starts so you can
actually make a wa it's top I can
explain this totally fine to anyone else
um when you are creating the steps to
reproduce the the attack you can just
say Okay first step is sign up for an
account and since there's no inhibitor
you can just go through the step up an
email and right exactly and go through
go through the process sure sure sure um
uh and so it would start with privilege
required none just check in general if
you are creating yeah yeah but if you're
creating a report in general do you
always get to decide from where the
attack starts like ignore the first half
of this attack this isn't actually the
attack and no no no no no I mean there's
no preconditions is all I'm saying like
it's a precondition related wait don't
look at the first half but like the
attack actually starts here is that like
a normal no no denied moving along you
don't get to talk on this
anymore do not hold this against me bug
Bounty Community I'm just checking I'm
just check trying my best here okay I'm
trying to understand where is this light
coming from it's that corner that corner
all right I'm going to adjust that real
quick yo y'all exciting announcement
real quick we are finally launching the
ctbb podcast swag store yeah that's
right the shirts that Joel and I have
been wearing on the Pod for the past
couple months will finally be available
for y'all to purchase at
cbb.com but if you didn't get your hands
on one or maybe you want some more then
uh definitely check out the swag store
also if you're a critical thinker on
Discord then uh check the Discord
Channel because you'll have a discount
code available for you there or maybe
this is a good opportunity for you to
sign up and become a critical thinker if
you're not already because you'll get a
great discount on the swag um if you do
so all right cool I think that's a wrap
uh anything else I need to tell you
about that I don't think so all right
cool back to the Pod let's
go um okay next one we're getting
technical now okay okay what is an idor
vulnerability an idor is an indirect
object reference yeah indirect idors I
like oh it's not object no incure direct
object oh no okay no that makes more
sense though that was pretty close
though an examp can I do an example of
an example an example of an idore is
when you're on a site right it's got
really bad security so it's got lots of
idor Y
and it'll say like in the URL or
something it can have like user equals
and then like a number yeah and then you
can if it's has poor security you can
just like change the number like 5
million to like 5 million and one and
then you get a different user perfect I
I I can see that you've heard me explain
this many times I like you have a
different o idor that I really like that
wasn't just like a plain numbers one
like a plus one plus one user integer
one yeah and you did one that was really
cool that was um you figured out how
they were creating user IDs based on
timestamps that was a while ago but I
really like that one so it was I found
one very similar at this last life
hacking event actually it's time stamp
from when they like created their
account or something like that so time
stamp from time of creation of account
down to like the millisecond or
something like ridiculous and then you
like figured out you just guessed that
that's how they did it and you figured
it out and it was like a really long
string of numbers and but it was an eyw
this is such a cute explanation of all
this no it's a good explanation very
good no it's very good you just
described I believe is a uuid V1 um
sandwich attack or idor um so that's the
sandwich attack that's what it was you I
should have remembered yeah your your
specialty
here um okay uh let me see what else we
got here
um what I kind of already covered this
but what is CVSs do you know what CVSs
is let me see if I can you don't have to
give me the acronym no I kind of want to
know the acronym because CVS is like the
scoring system of whether or not
something is you know from informative
to critical and I'm actually going to
look it up I think it's common
vulnerability scoring system yeah it is
scoring system so you get you get half
full half points for that full half
point oh I thank you for your generosity
you're welcome um so all right cool and
then we' got we got another technical
one and then we'll oh and then we'll do
a non-technical one um what is an xss
xss is crossy scripting good good can
you explain what it is not as well want
an ey door ey door is my
favorite um crossy scripting is so
you've got like the page right and you
on the right track you've got a web
page you
can sort of like paste your own Co code
over that web page so if you send
someone a link you can make them
Traverse through your malicious code to
the web page and have like both like a
pack it's like a package deal
that that is that is somewhat accurate
yeah exactly so you've got your
malicious page yeah yeah and then and
then how does the package deal well they
go through your link okay yes exactly
exactly they go through the link on on
our attacker page and then and it's
still like does it to their weite link
yes it's their website's link yes
instead of like bad guy. rhor raider.com
it's still like the the good oh my gosh
I need to register that right now I need
to put that DNS bad guy. rat.com that's
perfect that is where I'm going to host
all of my pscs from now
on yeah so then so then you're right so
they click our malicious link that is on
our website and then what happens to
their
website sucks up the bad website it
sucks up the bad website they can only
interact with the bad good
website yeah I mean that's pretty
accurate cuz
what what you're doing is you're running
code on their website right does that
make does that is that what you meant to
say but it's not but it's not you
haven't actually changed the website
that's right it's only in the the
victim's browser right other people
aren't seeing it yeah that's accurate
yeah very good very good very good
sweetheart you you rocked it okay last
one what is a good range for low
medium high and crit
bounties good Bounty range for each
thing yeah
[Laughter]
Theo should be at least 8K what oh my
gosh okay well you said I answered to
like not pro haacker on the other on so
I'm coming Pro haacker you are doing
perfectly um okay so we're talking about
like what is what would I expect to see
not what is like would be good CU like
would be good is probably higher in
general yes what is like maybe a a if
you look at a program you're like oh
that's a pretty good Bounty table when I
look at my programs what I'm looking for
right is like
at least 1K for lows onek for lows okay
great like out of the hundreds I feel
like it's pretty good okay yeah
um medium's around 5K I'm pretty sure
I've heard you say okay you're doing
you're doing great you're right on the
money at this point highs I guess I
don't it varies a lot from program to
program between a medium and a high
right it does yes so like 8K to 10K High
10K yeah sure 10K can be some crits too
so I'm sure there's like a they're
definitely program they pay 10K crits
and I I personally kind of like a really
wide range for crits like 10K does feel
like a crit payout to me but also like
30k would be awes to 100K crit payouts
like some of these companies should
definitely be paying 100K for yeah
Shopify has I think like 25 or maybe
it's 50 to 200k for crits um and so 50s
they low crit you may not ever get them
to pay it because of the way that their
vulnerability rating system works but um
the fact that it does exist and I I have
seen them pay it a couple times so yeah
that's a pretty big range you so you
like the bigger ranges on the crit you
know I do I'd rather be p as a hacker
right I'd rather be paid out 10K for a
crit than never be paid out 50k for a
crit yeah absolutely right yeah that's
just my personal that's I I agree I
think that's a great um I think that's a
great approach all right so that's all I
had for my questions you did very well I
going to give you a little round of
applause here those were like very very
Gable yeah yeah I think you did well um
okay so now I've got a couple sections
here in the doc that we can go over um
I'm really personally curious and
hopefully um I won't put you on the spot
too much to hear about your memories
from the live hacking events and the
show and tells because I know you've got
a couple that the show tells
specifically or just like story ideally
the show and tells because you know it's
like a it's like a hacking podcast you
know like we'd like to tell them about
hacking stories um but also
Mariah just just for for reference
Mariah has a lot better memory than I do
um and so when we talk about like our
history of our relationship and like uh
just in general um she has a better
recollection of of what's actually
happened normally so I was thinking we
could also go and cover a little history
of our our relationship plus bug Bounty
yeah yeah um so I think one of the
classic can we talk about like what who
was like sponsoring the event like who
was hosting the event at all of these
ones or no I would recommend not yeah
yeah um yeah cuz sometimes it's most of
the time it's not really relevant to
like the general feel of a live hacking
event but sometimes it's has been
relevant sometimes it is yeah for good
better for worse right no good good
question sweetie good question um so
let's talk a little bit
about the first live hacking event in
the story from your perspective because
um my first live hacking event was uh I
want to say it was H1 313 or something
like that in Washington DC which is like
close to where I live3 no no no no no no
this not
20138 2017 2017 yeah I did the wrong
2017 I think um and yeah uh it's an
interesting story of how I got into that
event and I've told that that story
before in the podcast so I kind of want
to hear Mariah's take on the
story do you remember at all yeah I know
I remember a lot about it sorry I hyped
you up I was like her memory is amazing
and then you're like I have idea have at
least 300 details about this event I'll
pair it down some the audience um at
that point in time we were like
massively in college debt still in
college this is a relevant part for me
we just started out okay no that's good
cuz like we were I mean we have like
flexible money now right at this point
in time we did not have flexible money
we had of flexible
money and Justin when he was like in
high school and I knew I had met him in
high school when he was in high school
when he was younger I knew he had like
done some like hacking stuff right but
then he sort of heard about bug Bounty
and then sort of started it like very
Loosely while we were like in college
and moving around and like very had a
lot going on but he was like doing this
for fun sometimes and I know he had had
some of the skill set beforehand um we
got married in end of junior year of
college just for for the record you know
sum I guess most of this time that I
knew about B Bounty I think we were
already in a serious relationship or
married so yeah yeah yeah
yeah
um so he got invited from this friend to
go to DC which is not was not it's not
far from where we live or lived and do
this thing and I feel like in college
it's such a good time to like do a ton
of things you haven't done right like I
went to in col College I went to like
tons of I went to like conferences of
different types I like tried different
things I would tried like 30 different
clubs at my school like I was definitely
in a habit of like trying multiple clubs
like
yeah nice nice I feel like we were in a
really good habit of trying things that
we didn't already like do right like
that's college is an awesome time to do
so many things you've never done so he
got invited to go to this conference is
sort of how it was pitched which live
hanging events are not at all like a
conference yeah um in DC
and he was like oh it's far and like we
already have a lot to do and I don't
know and I was like Justin so stupid you
you can drive to DC in a day and come
back and like meet people and like do
something you haven't done it was last
minute too it was last minute it was
like the next day yeah it was it was
like yeah super last minute and the
friend that invited you also you know
wasn't friend we hang out with all the
time so you know it wasn't like to see
your friend that you were going to go
right but yeah I was like you you're
doing this you're like having fun doing
it and he had just made some money off
of doing it like that week or the week
before something like super recently I
think I landed like one of my first
bounties it was like probably my third
or fourth but it was 20 $2,500 which was
like a good chunk really impactful
amount of money at that point in time
like a very noticeable like wow you just
like sat on your computer for part of a
weekend and like made a good chunk of
money that we can really use for our
lives so it was like worth noticing and
yeah I was like yeah definitely go and
then I think I don't even think I was
going to go with you in the first draft
and then cuz you were a plus one's plus
one so you didn't know you could bring
someone and then that just end up coming
or yeah you just ended up coming anyway
and we were like anyone I don't think we
did cuz it was like it was like we were
our the person that invited us was a
plus one and then I was the plus one of
the plus one and then you were my plus
one yeah and you were like I don't know
that you can come and I was like I don't
know that I can come I had like a paper
to write and stuff I had a lot of
writing to do in school oh you were
working I
working on home I was like drowning and
homework I couldn't have gone if I
didn't do more so yeah I showed up with
my laptop and I was like doing High
writing in a corner and I don't know if
they got any pictures of you but it's
really funny because uh you know Mariah
will come to most of the live hacking
events which we'll cover in a bit but um
and like she's been I think she's had a
whole page dedicated to her face in the
hacker one hacker report of her like and
and in in their defense like you know
most of the time when she's on her
computer
at these live hacking events she'll be
just doing something else but this time
you were actually doing like was it like
a training they did like a clinic it was
like
a women and hacking 101 or something it
was like in the middle of a live hacking
event it was kind of a strange setup for
it but yeah they were like it was like
let's install burp on your computer and
then like here's just some sandboxes and
stuff to like click around in and hack
and like then more instruction I was
just like hack this and you're like okay
well thanks for installing burp I guess
but I was like that was like the EXT of
the training it was really cool though
CU too cuz she was wearing glasses at
the time she since got lasic but she was
wearing glasses and like the shot was
over the computer and you can kind of
see this the computer screen like sort
of reflecting in her glasses at the time
so it was it was pretty let's Jump Ahead
to the event because we've been on the
story already for a while go ahead go
ahead so anyway he ends up choosing to
go to the event as a Plus+ plus and then
I ended up going long and being like
worst they can do is say no and we've
driven just a couple hours to DC and
he's going to go in anyway but um they
let me in and they let me just on my
computer in a corner and eat food and
stuff which is great and then meet
people I met a lot of people met a lot
of the OG staff at that point M um and
some hackers I remember
meeting John
bini classic classic bini I maybe I have
a lot of different names for a lot of
the hackers that are not their names not
not mean ones but like bottl tot is what
I usually call them CU it's just easier
to more I'm so sorry dude it it is what
happens though what what other names do
you have for other ha so many hacker
names um we have there's big Sam and
little Sam big Sam little Sam um we're
not going to tell you which ones are are
which both of them have been on the
podcast has nothing to do with sizes
it's like a Vibe you know yeah size a
person size is all about their Vibe um
we have little Jack but he's not around
too much anymore jack isn't around
anymore um a lot of people I actually
know their hacker names and their hacker
handles their real names or their hacker
handles and like use both or either of
them I'm trying to think if I have any
more like out of left field names I
can't think of any off the top of my
head okay what other memories do you
have from that original event
um I remember the show and tell
specifically at that one because I've
been to a lot of live hacking events and
seen the show in tells and like not
remembered a lot of it but I remember
like cuz Justin was wasn't fron at that
event fron was at that event I remember
Justin was like crazy about fr he was
like this is the super super good hacker
from Sweden and like I'm like I was like
Justus just go like talk to we're like
in this like very small she literally
made me go talk to him like he had found
some I think this was like like I want
to ask him about this bug he had found
this crazy bug I think it was a supply
chain related bug um at the time and
that was like not anything like nobody
was doing that at the time and uh and I
was like I don't understand how this
works I need to go figure out how this
works and and but I was like I can't
really go up and talk to him so stupid
like this is lit this guy could
literally just be a Joe off the street
like just talk he's only famous to you
I'm sure he's famous for many people but
like we're like in a very intimate
setting like some of the venues are very
big some of the venues are very closed
off right like lots of closable doors
and I know that that makes I think
intentionally right some of the hackers
less accessible they would just want to
focus and work and I think that's
totally fine to respect that there
wasn't closed off spaces it was like a
very open floor plan and so I was like
just like this very small this is not a
conference for one we we arrived and
like we're very sure it was not a
conference we're like in a very intimate
setting like just go if you're here then
you can go say hi like this is not like
a it's not that kind of thing so he talk
to him and that was cool for him and I
got talked to some random hackers I
figured out France is a is a person yeah
I crazy crazy he's not like some hacking
God that's that's like a takeaway though
like if you do go to a live hacking
event for the first time or the 10th
time or whatever and you're like afraid
to meet people just go talk to them and
like if they're jerks that's on them you
know some people are jerks that's just
how people are but like most people are
very open and like people cuz I feel
like that's a pretty easy default to
assume like if you are at the event you
can have a conversation with people at
the event so I mean I do I go to a lot
of events I have conversations with lots
of people and I don't I certainly
haven't earned my way to the events you
definitely have some some like good
friendships with some top hackers and
their and their girlfriends too which is
great um and so uh all right so that's
that's the DC story oh uh do you
remember anything from the shows this
like one of the first showels I ever saw
was um en's yeah and in was like super
memorable like a really interesting guy
I don't remember like meeting him or
having conversations with him but like
he got up there and was like a great
presenter and he played this like video
song that um about hacking and Justin
has told me it's it's rubies Ruby Neon
made that song but like at the time I
was like what is happening there's like
a whole subculture of like hack music
like what what is this and then 's
presentation was just really good I
could tell you what it does I've seen
like tons of good presentations and
memorable things since then I like um
Sam Curry's null boys oh null boys he
put a lot of null boys
into giving him information back that's
right that's right that's that's an
accurate I mean that's pretty much the
whole presentation the whole bug was
like he put in a and then somehow that
null bite was getting uh filled with
just random pieces of memory from the
server and so he could just leak massive
chunks of memory from the server um
that's a good that's a good memory I me
some of these presentations are really
memorable that's not on me that's I love
that yeah yeah they did they did a good
job zero opsc on this guy oh Zer that's
donut that was donut donut yeah that was
a what sorry maybe the target's not no
no no no no no it's fine uh that was a
the target doesn't matter someone gave
him like part of their social security
number part of it to test to see if he
could get the rest of it but Social
Security numbers are already not that
long so this person gives him part of a
social security number and in the
presentation he got zero obsc on that
guy yeah like you got to give people
your social security number test a
hilarious moment that was so good I
loved that but Jonah got it that's why
he's doing Trel so it it worked and he
did get more Social Security numbers
than just that guy with the zero OBC but
yeah yeah that was that was lovely that
was that was a great show tell what
other do you have any other ones off the
top of your head I'm trying to think I
love all of random deductions Jo and she
awesome hearing her talk yeah especially
the LA event last year was phenomenal so
um there have been some poems oh my gosh
there have and and crew have done some
like Li one of them was like Dr Seuss it
was you're right um
I'm sure I remember more I've and I know
I've learned content from a lot of them
some of them just start sounding kind of
the same you know do you remember so
that that first event do you remember
what bug in was presenting on at all do
you remember any of the details about
the bug or like the song that he played
I I usually remember the song I'm having
trouble right now just a second we we'll
link the song in the description it's
like I hope it's still up I got to go
track it down but uh I can't remember
right now it's a it's um hey some dat
content injection song you remember that
there's a Content
injection on your I just kept
remembering it kept stopping at the
Y injection on and like so you don't
really I don't remember a lot of the bug
cuz that's the content I got I like
where's the content
injection oh such a good such a good
memory um all right solid good oh you
know what another really good one was I
think it was um
oxac and Fisher yeah they got a
massive was that the one where they um
just changed the just a second um
default password reset email or
something like that yeah you could just
[Applause]
change you could just instead of like H
trying to hack someone's password they
just said just kidding sent my password
reset token to my email oh my gosh yeah
that one was a really good one I like
the ones that are just like that that
are like so stupid yeah yeah like you
could I mean you didn't even need burp
for that one like you literally could
just type it in wait a second don't send
it to this email send every pathw res
set to my email that was crazy that was
crazy that was that's that's a good a
good memory that was I think that was
one of the first bugs that I'd seen that
got I don't know if we can say how much
it got paid out but it was like a very
large amount um and it was very
staggering at the time yeah yeah um so
yeah I I agree that was that was a great
one too um so let's see let's let's skip
forward a little bit um so you know we
did that first event and then you and I
kind of went to a couple events since
and and um you know when when we didn't
have kids then we were going to we were
going to all of these events together
yeah I mean over I've been to probably
about 20 life hacking events yeah
personally and just been to like a few
more than I have yeah um so that that
that was great it's been a great
opportunity to travel around do you have
any tips for people bringing their wives
or girlfriends on trips to live hacking
events for the h so tips tips let me let
me clarify tips for the hacker and tips
for the girlfriend I love that I feel
like people do it very differently right
like depending on personalities I've
seen it done a lot of Way by haggers and
their Partners um some I know that
Justin when he goes to a life hacking
event he takes a very seriously and
wants to really respect the the program
and the company you know everyone flying
him out and
stuff so he will
spend 98 and a half% of every trip we
take like actually hacking the target
some hackers do not do that so if you're
not a hacker who like cares to do that I
know a lot of people will like take the
plane ticket and hack beforehand
hopefully be respectful to the programs
and stuff but hack beforehand and then
during the event just kind of enjoy you
know the cool City or whatever they're
flying you out to that's totally
different right like if they were taking
time off to like be with their partner
and travel together you can do whatever
you want as like a couple have fun chill
do whatever we don't do it that way J
very serious about his hacking
so I for I guess for any Partners who
are the plus ones on the sidelines for
the things I had to do a lot of work to
like not demand his time during those
times and like not try to drain or pull
or like complain him away from the
things that he's doing cuz they are very
important and I want to be respectful of
his Hobby and also his job um and his
Focus you know like it takes a lot it
takes a lot to hack these targets that's
kind of the point so for me it was a lot
of like okay if I'm going I am there to
be supportive I am not there to take his
time I'm hopefully there to maybe make
some things more efficient for him um
help to make some more money for both of
us I love that for us and like let him
let him kind of be um so it really
depends on the locations that we've gone
to what I've done a couple times and for
some of the longer ones most the time
they're a weekend which is chill for
some of the longer ones like out of the
country or so Vegas is so long I've like
brought friends or family and like just
you know forgot about Justin and done
whatever I wanted done a lot of planning
like today we're going to take a a bus
tour and the next day we're going to
rent a car and like drive here and go
kaying and like do all this stuff that
Justin has not gotten to do on his
vacation yeah I've never I've been to
Vegas five or six times at this point
and I've never been to the Grand Canyon
it's like the easiest thing to get to
like every single time we go I I am just
lasered in on work and then by the time
I'm done like after Vegas you're just
toasted you know you just want to go
home especially Vegas yeah um but it's
Mariah's seen the Grand Canyon like
three times and and I've never been
that's beautiful that's great yeah I
still haven't um r a donkey down into
what I've never been been into it which
I feel like has got to be the best way
to see it but uh maybe sometime you do a
helicopter over it no I'm not bougie
like that Justin is a very bougie so
sometimes it's nice to notel very Bouie
I'm not very bie okay I forgot the
audience we're talking to the guys troll
me all the time like all the hackers are
like who we're talking to Justin spend
money not Bouie yeah compared to you
guys yeah um he just has more like he
would take a helicopter ride and I would
take a donkey you know like this is the
L this is the level
but he would not take a private jet over
the grand gon so he's not like bougie
bougie thank you um or waste $10,000
gambling he would not do that yeah
actually yeah so thanks yeah you're
welcome um so so okay so going going
back you're saying there's a little bit
of a mindset shift for you so much of a
mindset sh and I know some couples
aren't like that right some couples
don't aren't there to spend as much time
as possible with their partner and I
totally get that too but that's not what
I do what in general yeah and and I
think you you had a good tip and I think
we've had a fun time with it too when
you're able to bring a friend with you
yeah that's fun yeah a lot of the
weekends though I'll like maybe I'll try
to plan something that I know Justin
might want to do and like maybe some
hackers can join along we do a lot of
little stuff we'll go to like a museum
is such a bad example but we have done
that before I know Justin doesn't like
museums so much I don't love museums
totally okay yeah well but like an event
that we can like maybe tag a couple
hackers on to that he and his buddies
can come to to to and like have a fun
time for like an evening we usually have
at least an evening to do something
together and in general I just kind of
like try to get in my mindset sometimes
I'll have like work I need to do on my
computer sometimes I'll have just you
know chill and enjoy the hotel View and
like the little food with the hackers
and like see some old buddies now and
but yeah sometimes I'll do stuff for
myself and I think that's a really
personal decision you know if
you depends on how much work you want to
do for yourself how much planning you
want to do for yourself if you can
choose to have a fun time traveling by
yourself in a really cool City that
you're not paying for like that's
obviously going to be the best but if
it's not worth the effort then don't go
or chill or do whatever you want has
that been for you what like like do you
think you Vancouver was one that you
were incredibly busy for I remember this
is like years ago now you were like so
busy and so unavailable which was
disappointing and early so I still
wasn't as good as like letting you be
but Vancouver was so awesome like so
beautiful like you can't you can go and
have a fun time alone in Van you know
some of the places just haven't really
been worth it to me to like go through
the effort of having a good time by
myself right but I I really do feel like
that's personal and I think I generally
have if I pick at least one or two
things I want to see and either invite
you to them and see if you can do them
with me or say like I am going to have a
fun time and I am going to see the one
or two things I really wanted to see
even if he's not free to do them with me
that's been that's been best for me just
like do one or two good things make
yourself some good memories you can take
home and like make it worth your time
for going yeah yeah that makes sense
yeah I think uh I think it can
definitely be a very intense time and I
think hacker one has evolved a little
bit now to have that extra day on the
end normally after the hacking is done
because I think in the beginning they
were kind of playing with a little bit
and they would try to do like Community
day before the event but the thing is
the people that are really competitive
are or really taking it seriously are
still thinking about hacking that whole
time yeah so it's much nicer to have it
on the back end of that where now
everything's out of my brain
everything's done you can't even
everything's dup now anyway everything's
a dke now anyway that's too real um you
know or the submissions are closed right
and um and then you can go and have a a
relaxing day together yeah yeah exactly
that's great and like they often will do
something so fun like we've like boed
down the temps you know like and we've
gone to see like a NBA game you know
just like random stuff that is like
scheduled and there's a bus and like you
go and the hackers go you know so like
we've gotten to do a bunch they'll get
me tickets too which is great we've like
grown into that right the more I like
showed up the more we've like grown into
because you know I was I didn't even ask
the first time and I wasn't sure if I'd
get through the door now I get through
the door but they boot me out for
showing tals so I don't have many recent
show and tells because they're all like
you know
what hearing about bugs live on our Ser
can go sell that information to nation
state or something I don't know you know
ites sense it's just not as fun you know
but it it makes sense should have some
ndas there and then you can just sign it
and stay you yeah I mean but if you're
going to sell an sell information for
millions of dollars and NDA is not going
to stop you from selling information
millions of dollars well then it doesn't
it doesn't you know do anything anyway
it doesn't do anything any it doesn't do
anything it's it's it's a lawyer thing
for sure it's limited liability I get it
you don't need Rando watching it just
it's just more fun to watch yeah that
makes sense um what it had like what was
your favorite activity that you've done
at a live hacking event um either as a
part of like hacker one sponsored stuff
or I think voting the Tams was the the
best I mean you can't be boting the Tims
yeah that was really good that was the
first time I've been to
London and like probably not something I
would have sprung for if I if we had
been on a trip ourselves you know I'd be
like oh renting a boat it's probably not
even Tim is it t tames I have no idea
what it is yeah um that nice big river
in Big Old River by the clock that was
that was that big old other building
that was really that was really fun time
I agree I think boating excursions so
nice really nice uh Integrity also did
one of those for uh an event I think it
was Portugal and uh that one was a
little bit choppier but it was still
amazing yeah yeah so I think um I have
really been grateful to be included on
like events like that with hacker one
specifically um to not be program or
like platform agnostic they have been
very kind to me as a way to incentivize
Justin to Contin you to do a good job
which has been very effective for them
so I think it's a good investment on
their part yeah I'm sure there's like a
hundred great things we've done I'm not
thinking of all of them right now but
some of the favorite things that I've
done is like we went to Spain for a big
live hacking event yeah and I had my
family and a really good friend um Kodi
there with us and I had like this
massive itinerary that I made for us and
like we were just like doing stuff and
seeing stuff for days and days we walked
like Barcelona was beautiful too
Barcelona was so beautiful and never
been and we walked like 20,000 steps a
day and saw like a billion things and
then from Barcelona we took a big trip
that I planned around Europe to like
andur France um Monaco yeah we like
swung around the coast and like did all
the things that I wanted to do cuz I
planned it and we just saw so many cool
things carasol in friends was really
pretty so just like you know that's how
we've done it especially on the bigger
trips like International trips is we've
like pivoted it to you can change your
flight out to whenever you want it
doesn't have to be the day they stop
paying for your hotel which I don't know
if that's common knowledge but you can
ask them to fly you out five weeks later
if you want to spend some extra time in
Japan or whatever like I think there's
like a limit maybe not five weeks yeah
might be like two weeks or something but
you know talk to theun yeah they can
make it happen so we've like pivoted and
had a lot of fun with that um yeah you
know just work with your partner figure
out what they want to do figure out what
you want to do and if it doesn't sound
fun to be alone for an entire weekend
then um maybe don't do it if that's the
partner you have okay so switching
switching uh speed a little bit here
away from the live hacking events um one
of the things I've talked to the
audience on critical thinking a about a
lot is how um you ha were really pivotal
in the decision to go full-time bug
Bounty and then me maintaining my mental
health dur you know while doing
full-time book Bounty for so long
specifically in the arena of like not
putting myself worth in my performance
as a hacker yeah um so can you talk a
little bit about that decision to go
full-time Buck Bounty and
you know what our thought process was
like and then also not finding your self
worth in in your uh you know performance
as a hacker well I think
that he could have started full-time bug
Bounty like a lot before he did like he
chose to get a full-time job out of
college and do bug Bounty because
remember we were still in college when
he went to his first life hacking event
even and then after that was pretty
often you every few months and being
invited to more events and stuff so he
seemed like he is doing well but he
still like accepted a full-time job out
of college and did that for a year or
two for a while um also Justin you know
most people don't have this problem
Justin has never failed to get a job
he's applied for right like Justin has
gotten jobs he hasn't applied for just
people will be your big Justin please
work for us this is real coming from
someone who doesn't have the same
experience and has like gone months you
know looking for a job and trying to get
something that works for me me and like
then not liked my jobs like had a much
more difficult and unpleasant like job
in general had many more job interviews
where I didn't get the job it's it's
totally different right and your skill
set's in demand and your personality is
in demand you're just very lovable and
likable and great a great asset on the
team thank you so coming from
specifically where he was he did not
need a job out of college he did not
need it to ensure that he would get a
job later in life like
he he will always be employable
if he stays how he is even if he doesn't
improve for the rest of his life right
if he stays how he is he is incredibly
employable so that would be I think
maybe the biggest concern for people if
you know you were transitioning out of
college is like what if I feel like this
like what if I you know then have like a
two-year resume Gap or whatever whatever
one he was already being very successful
like he was already finding bugs in his
very very limited time I made sure it
was very limited because he was working
a full-time job and we were recently
married so very limited amount of time
he had to hack he was finding stuff
right
and I think that Ma I think that matters
you know and especially like if you
don't know you want to do it you want to
make sure you're in a position that you
can get a job like I think wanting a
bailout from bu Bounty is totally
reasonable that just wasn't a problem
for you and we we had we had Financial
margin we had um a track record of me
doing BG B parttime and making almost as
much or more actually than my full-time
salary yeah and you had done that for
like a year and I had tried to again I
had like tried to let him hack a little
bit but the full-time job plus bug
Bounty was not for an early marriage in
my opinion not it's not great yeah it it
was hard in the beginning for sure I
mean you add anything to a full-time job
in early marriage like grad school or
any other commitment to your time and
it's probably I mean just be married
that's my vote but but you know it's
something you really like something
you're really good at it did it but it
would worked out as a pivot it did not
work out as a long-term bug Bounty and
full-time job and that's part of why I
really pushed it part why I still push
it this guy still is like what if I got
a job or what if I started another
company or what if I had 16 more
different well both but that's true I I
would I I definitely considered job
offers from Google and from uh like a
government entity uh so I think I think
that but yeah lately more so on the
entrepreneurial side they're like
wouldn't it be great if I just like
started this other company and you're
like literally don't even think about it
yeah so for us like he
I think you even paid down our college
debt while we were still in college in
our like in our like one year of college
we went from like you know COL two
people of Collegiate debt to like wait
we just positive zero yeah we're like
we're not negative anymore that's crazy
and that to us was really important we
didn't want to like hold all of the
loans and like hold the weight from
other loans so we chose to pay all those
down um and so we already saw that like
he could make money from it and so I
more than him was like okay so when are
you quitting your job as soon as you got
a job like this is
not this and this is like not awesome
and clearly this one is working better
for us do you remember how I responded
to that at the time because I feel like
we've merged our mentalities so much no
unstable income well healthc care what
oh that's sorry that's how I remember it
oh my gosh I just never know if I'm
going to get paid though like what if
they just stop paying me money for the
bugs that I find so that's how I
remember wow okay well hey that should
be an man I can hear my um my mentees
right now just laughing their heads off
because now I have so much you know
merged this mentality with Mariah um and
by merge I mean taken her
mentality about it that I'm like
constantly yelling at my friends that
are doing well in P Bounty like hey dude
if you don't want to be at this job that
you hate Just J Bounty yeah yeah like
you can take the risk now is the time to
take it you're young you don't have any
you know additional things you need to
pay or responsibilities or anything
spouses or single some of them are yeah
exactly and and so like I think that
there's a lot of yeah flexibility that I
see now that I didn't see at the time
and I was glad you I was really glad you
had the foresight to see that you also I
mean I was really pushing for it it was
you're often a pretty big risk averse
guy right and so by the time we made the
decision we it wasn't a risk it truly
was there was no risk in it you had
months of success months of at least
being able to pay our bills on such a
small amount of time invested and yeah I
think I think when you chose to do it
you chose to do it zero risk really and
like I said you're very you personally
are very employable so worst case
scenario you get a job again which puts
you exactly back where you were right um
but you also liked your job and you
liked your co-workers and so I get that
I mean there's a lot that needs to go
into decision to being full-time bug
bounty like if you don't want to be home
alone or at a cafe alone every single
day of your life like that's a super
reasonable decision Justin loves to wall
himself off and like focus on his work
for an entire day for an entire week you
know like that Vibes with you like
that's great I could not do it would not
do it you're do you do great at it works
for you but yeah I think by the time we
decided to do it it was like really no
risk like you had enough of a track
record you were employable again felt
like such a risk to me man it felt like
such a risk but but you know you're
right I mean we had a track record we
had Financial margin saing when you when
you when you think about I just hear
these stories of people being like all
right well I'm gonna like put my rent on
a credit card to like do this thing that
I really want to do and I'm
like that is that is uh that is dicey
you know and uh and so there are
definitely people out there that take a
lot more risk than we did in that
situation um Okay so you know the
question yeah yeah yeah well that that
answer the question about like going
fulltime bug Bounty you know that was
our thought process of like we earned
enough you know we had minimized the
risk we were going to move to Japan
right that was that same time um I
really do feel like it's such a personal
decision and I think it's a personal
decision to start and a personal
decision to continue right and so we've
made both you chose to start and many
people will try full-time bug Bounty and
get hit some of the cons and say this
isn't for me and that's totally fine
like a lot people have done it for years
and then been like hey I don't like
hustling this much like I don't like
earning every penny I make like
correlatively right like I want to be
able to show up and do a good job at my
job and get paid whether or not which is
fair yeah I think that's totally fair
yeah and it's like and you can clock out
at the end of the day you know some
people have a hard time um quitting work
when they are doing full-time bug Bounty
you know it's it's all personal
decisions and that's totally fine um for
us though the continued decision is
based on all the pros right so like the
cons are still there what what cons have
I experienced in full-time bug Bounty
definitely I me which ones have you
talked me out of Slash uh suppored me
through the ones I've seen for you are
not the ones that I see for the most
commonly honestly like the isolation is
not a problem for you yeah no um and I
manage his social calendar a little bit
so that he doesn't have he doesn't
become like a so I don't lose the
friends that I already have exactly yeah
um but like the work isolation is not a
problem for you and the making enough
money is not a problem for you right I
know some hackers especially when
they're just starting like it's hard to
like actually be making enough money to
pay your bills which I think is fair um
those are like maybe the two most
serious problems that can happen Justin
doesn't have those so I'd say your next
problems you hit are
like it's like I am garbage if I'm not
making enough money for my family and
enough money is like subjective he's
always making enough money for us to
like live and be well but I I'll set
aggressive goals for it yeah which is
great I think aggressive goals are also
awesome they work great for you um until
they don't right and then also like that
it's not working spiral of
like this I love how she's got a name
for this that it's not working spiral
need to put that on a t-shirt a bug this
one was a dupe I found an almost bug it
ended up not being a bug you know like
you hit a couple different flavored
lumps you know yeah like you had a
couple different problems flavored lumps
and then and then it gets into the I'm
not work it's not working spiral right
and then especially this is the first
like year or two right we're like more
than that into it but the first year or
two especially like you hit like two
dupes in a month and you're like this
was supposed to pay my bills or you and
like this one triager is like mean or
wrong and you have to tell them
something seven times you know like this
is a bug I need it to be a bug and it's
a bug like you know like you had a
couple different things and then you
start rethink you start wasting your
time rethinking your life decisions and
you know it makes sense to like lose
motivation and like lose energy
temporarily when you're disappointed
right that's just what disappointment in
life does sometimes but like but then to
start wasting your time rethinking all
of your decisions and being like maybe
I'm not cut out for this like it is
truly a waste of time to re-evaluate
that's maybe another good takeaway if
you're going to do full-time bug Bounty
or you're going to try it right you're
in transition don't waste your time
reevaluating just commit to it hard give
yourself yeah whatever savings you have
whatever time you have 3 months and also
don't miss metric right like sometimes
this happens to you too sometimes Justin
will be like I can like therapy okay all
right I didn't find enough bugs this
month right whatever that is I didn't I
wasn't as successful as much month as I
wanted you know now I'm rethinking
decisions okay we're going to pause it
we're going to actually look at what
you've done cuz usually when that
happens for Justin it's like yeah well
we went on a vacation for like 9 days we
had like this thing implode in our
social life we had like this family
member that needed something we had
three hour work dayss for two weeks
straight and the vacation for the rest
of the month like oh no you didn't find
a full-time like 40 hour work weeks
worth of bugs every single week for four
weeks when not a single week was a real
work week like don't get caught up on
that if you're going to throw a pity
party like you need to have actually
worked for hours a week to then be like
wait maybe this isn't working so you
guys see this is what I get like just to
be clear like like you know I think I
show up to these podcasts like you know
pretty amp for bug Bounty and like and
like pretty in favor of it but there are
sometimes when I'm really down about it
and then she gives me one of these like
yeah what the heck are you doing uh pep
talks where we we talk through all of
the benefits of of the lifestyle that we
have with full-time bug Bounty and it
makes me realize that oh my my dup
streak or like you know me having to
respond to this report you know five
times before the triage triages it is
not actually that bad and this is a a
really awesome set or sometimes I think
unfairly programs have like underrated
bugs you know programs make mistakes
there are a lot of problems you'll run
into but if you're truly reconsidering
doing full-time bug Bounty you need to
make sure all your information right
like you may not re-evaluate if you
haven't gotten your results that you
want if you also haven't done the work
that you needed to do right like and
it's easy for not reevaluate she you
need to decide beforehand like you just
I've just see so many hackers some of
your mes that I won't call out by name
yeah and like just hackers in general
wasting so much time and energy
re-evaluating based on garbage facts
right like you got to get your facts
right you got to know how much you're
putting into it before you evaluating H
how well you're doing or what you're
getting out of it like you have to make
sure you're output is is matching you
what you you know it's just not worth
you cannot waste that much time
reevaluating that I've seen some people
waste yeah I I feel that so um you know
you just great gave an excellent pep
talk to me in this in this situation and
all the hackers listening so hopefully
uh people will take that um could you
could you take a moment
to brag on yourself a little bit and if
you don't then I will uh
on like
how having a a stable supportive
relationship is is important for
full-time bug Bounty and like you want
me to tell them how important that I am
to your success exactly that is what I
want or would you like me to do it I can
do it too I feel like people are so
different you know like I know our
relationship is not going to be
everyone's
relationship
um I also I think I saw in your doc some
of the things like how to be a better
like hacker spouse like as the hacker
part two I'd love to go into that some
um yeah well you know and for us okay
I'm I'm not GNA try to give super
broadly applicable advice because it's
too broad so all I can say what I do to
support you and so one of the biggest
things we did was we were both working
full-time jobs and
doing hacking on the side right so
full-time full-time above full-time
right
that was not it for us that did not work
we were like stressed I would get home
from work he would stay homeworking for
both of his jobs I would get home from
work we would have like no food no one
to cook if we cooked neither of us
wanted to clean up it was like very bad
vibes like and understandably because
we're both exhausted it's like 6:30
we'll have maybe maybe as late as 7 when
we finish like making eating dinner we
like ate out a lot which we don't like
to do all the
time and then we' just be exhausted we
just go to bed and start the next day
and I I don't like that life cycle right
like I know that's a really probably the
most at least in America the most common
life cycle is like you spend your entire
day working you spend your entire
evening staying alive barely living
getting behind on your your crap that
you will need to do pushing that till
Saturday like oh I need to clean the
house or I need to like go grocery
shopping and like meal prep or whatever
and then you start your next week
already and that for us was like this is
such a bad lifestyle what what can we do
at this point to change that so I quit
my job which was great you know like it
I'm very Pro like domestic tasks are not
for the females alone you know like
labor should be split
equally but then we just reduce the
labor dramatically by me quitting a job
right which and so now I can take
domestic tasks and and more and and our
real estate portfolio and that sort of
thing yeah like Property Management like
meal prep meal planning grocery shopping
all the laundry I will often personally
like make and deliver food to Justin's
desk and then like clean up his desk and
garbage after afterwards and and like
that to me is is totally fine and
sometimes it's not and sometimes I'm
like Justin I feel like you're treating
me like a maid and then we have that
conversation and then we fix it you know
I'll try to be I'll try to be I mean it
it es and flows with my level of
engagement on that front as well because
sometimes I'll just be so in the zone
and then I'll look down and there's food
and then I'll you know eat it and then I
I'll I'll get back in the zone I look
down and the Plate's gone and I'm like
what
this is real for him too like his focus
is crazy he he is if anything too
focused which I know is not a problem
most people have um yeah so for me I you
know I've just taken on a lot of the
stuff I taken on our whole social
calendar like I said I actively plan him
like play dates with his friends and
like play dates you don't have to act
like I'm a kid gez you can play with by
the way when's the next play I know uh
um so I think that I think that's a big
piece and I put a lot of like planning
and work into our like vacations like
our family vacation stuff I tons of
research and planning and stuff and I
just take on what I feel like I can take
on for us that's how we've distributed
labor and for us that works as like
hacker couple and it's a really good way
to support him so it takes a lot of the
mental load off of him intentionally
right like he doesn't have to think
about what we're eating he doesn't have
to think about his macros right there's
going to be like a protein for dinner
you know like or worry about it and like
I also do a lot of driving for our kid
and stuff too so I also wanted to so on
on the kid note you know we recently we
recently have a kid in our home and
um there's there's definitely some
changes that come along with that uh and
I think one of the great things about
being full-time book Bounty was when uh
the kid is away at school um we also can
have time together right because you're
I'm self-employed and you are also
self-employed right so we can adjust our
schedules and even if that means I need
to work a little bit later or something
like that we can still go on a date or
like hang out or whatever um and that
and and talk you know CU by the time you
get your kid to bed sometimes it's like
oh I'm just going to fall asleep um so I
think that's been really positive for us
as well um for me too I mean especially
since we're both at home right so if
both people are at home Justin has said
that like if he's hacking and I come in
and ask him like a random question right
like what about tomorrow what about this
plan whatever and then he has to go back
to hacking it wastes like 10 to 15
minutes of cognitive time for him and
that like correlated to like our per
hour wage
is important right like I don't want to
waste 15 minutes of your time yeah
unnecessarily right you're you're very
cognizant of that now and I think that's
been an evolution huge change but yeah I
I think when she'll group things too so
she'll come in you know she still come
in and interrupt me from time to time
but it's like she's got three disjointed
questions you know that she clearly has
been stacking up yeah um and then we'll
get those done and then knock it out and
we'll we'll go along if it like I
appreciate that a lot cuz you know I I
respect my own time as well so if it if
the things are too much in the way of me
getting what I need done done you know
like this is a house decision we need to
make this is a school thing and this is
a social thing I got three and a half
people waiting for
me and now I can't really like do the
rest of my stuff before I get back to
these people on these things yeah I'll
I'll for sure interrupt him but like for
me it was definitely a big change from
being like you know I very much
value like people respecting my time and
like if I need something like responding
to that right but in within like the
bounds of it's just boundaries for
working at home right like within the
boundaries of working at home and clear
expectations you know you want to
respect each other's time so yeah could
you could you talk a little bit about uh
the goal system that you set up to
motivate me and how that's worked in uh
our bug Bounty career yeah I think part
of it so if you're doing bug Bounty
you're assuming a lot of
work right you have a lot of work you
got a lot of emotional ups and downs
like life hacking events are one thing
just month-to month dayto day people not
paying you what you hope to be paid this
you know even just hitting one dupe you
know that's always a huge bummer like
you have expected something and it
didn't come through
so one thing because it's a bounty
system and the more work the more you
can focus the more you can have fun the
more you can make your life Pleasant
instead of miserable right really the
more money you make in bug Bounty like
if you're just sitting there miserable
you're probably
yeah you're probably not focusing well
you're probably not excited to try
something new you're probably not in it
and if you're not in it you're not going
to be making money it's such a weird
system like that let let me I'm gonna
just pause you for just a second because
there's a an article by Sam Curry on why
it's entitled I think why you shouldn't
become a bug bounty hunter or something
like that um and I'm not sure I agree
with all of the takes in there I think
we've mentioned it on the podcast once
or twice but um I do agree that when you
are happy and when you are focused and
you are like enjoying the process of bug
Bounty itself then you will get better
results by a long shot um and this also
ties back into the self-worth
conversation that we'll we'll swing back
around to because I want to talk about
that again um but you know there's also
other ways to to incentivize and make
sure that you're having a happy
motivated time like this goal system so
yeah go on that and there really are a
lot of cons doing bug Bounty right it's
way more emotional than you'd ever be at
uh regular salary job right it's it's a
lot of work you got to do internal work
you got to collaborate with your partner
a lot because expectations change a lot
doesn't C even just like live hacking
schedule to not live hacking schedu is a
lot but like hey I'm on like the trail
of this bug I need like another hour
tonight you know like your everyday
expectations might change a lot and so
given the cons of it you just yeah you
just got to keep things prioritized man
yeah so the goals the goal system that
we set up I guess
surrounding the liveing events this is
speaking to motivation that's why I was
talking about that so you you want to
keep yourself positively motivated for
how much work you're getting you're
doing it so this was a system I think I
just came up with it yeah you came up
with it because we generally are pretty
Frugal and we were right at first we
were like paying off all our College
debts and then we were like saving money
so that we weren't like like we could
have some flexibility exactly like and
keep some Savings in the bank and then
we were like choosing to go to these
live hacking events and like not really
do anything like not celebrate them not
have a lot of fun cuz we were just in
the like pay off the debt mindset and I
was like this isn't this isn't Fun and
if it's not fun it's not going to keep
going well so we pretty early on we did
like a goal system right so he would
come up with goals for
himself and tiar them so like if I make
like 10 monies I'll get 10
monies so much this is like a 1 to 10
scale right if I make 10 monies this is
like the grand prize if I make like
seven monies this is the next prize and
if I make like four monies this is my
like low ball prize so like if he makes
and then if he doesn't reach even his
lowest goal which is aggressive for
Justin generally then he doesn't we just
don't we don't get a price he pretty
much always gets at least his lowest
goal um I don't know that you've ever
not gotten your lowest goal I don't
think so maybe once maybe but um the
lowest one is usually like a$1 to $200
Prize or one one1 to $5500 prize like a
new coffee maker you know like an
appliance
is is already a couple hundred dollars
you know so we'll do something that my
next coffee maker will be more than a
couple hundred dollars but we'll get to
that
later or like this one like a pullup bar
for the garage you know installed or
something like that like you know it'll
be like something little but something
and even something maybe we would have
wanted to do anyway but we'll try to
like prolong it a little bit to like be
a reward instead of just be something
that we sink money into and then like
the biggest you got a car off of one of
them yeah and uh and a hot tub right hot
tub really the biggest one like I I I
think that one is the one that had the
most value and I think it's interesting
because obviously you know we're making
enough money where where we could just
go buy any of these things but I think
gamifying it as well really uh appeals
to me you oh you didn't get the hot tub
this time guess we'll have to wait till
next time and I think I think also
Mariah very
emphatically insistent that I I follow
through with the purchase after the
event uh was was really big because you
know I'd be like oh well you know it's
like $7,000 for this hot tub or whatever
Plus the electrical it was like at Le I
don't know it was a lot for the
electrical the hot tub and we had to get
a patio under the hot tub to like have a
flat surface yeah so it was a lot uh but
you were insistent that I followed
through with that because that's you
have to keep those promises to yourself
and and and it it I think that was that
was great that was kind of what what we
needed there and it's always a
percentage right like if he makes you
know $20,000 an event he's never going
to spend $20,000 from that event oh no
yeah on it's like a small toys right on
stuff we don't need I mean we might well
we'll spend it on like rent and
Investments and stuff but we're not
going to spend it for fun it's always
like a scaling percentage of so if he
makes a little money he gets a little
thing and if he makes a lot of money he
gets a bigger thing but it's still like
not you know we're not going to spend
all of the money at once and that's a
personal finance decision for us too is
we don't want like lifestyle creep to
control our entire lives and we really
don't want to chop ourselves into having
to make as much money as we're making
now either right like we want to live
below our means so that if we do ever
want to Pivot for any reason and
honestly like we've had this kid uh kid
since um May some sometime some some
some undisclosed time yeah I don't know
what month it is honestly anyway but a
few months and like our he has worked so
much less right like we've been we
spending a lot of time strategizing like
oh what do we do like this is a new
thing we've never done before you know
this is a half-grown child like she's
already come with a lot of
pre-programming and like we're you know
we're every week not every day every
week there's something like you know
we've never seen this before in our life
and now we're parenting it parenting is
interesting yeah so we've chosen to
spend a ton of time on it like and he
has not for months and months not worked
probably one full work week maybe a full
week on a live hacking event yeah except
for the live hacking events think that's
true you know there's been a lot of
fragmentation but think uh I think we're
working back towards that that direction
uh of getting fulltime you know getting
dedicated hacking time in place um but
it it's definitely an adjustment and the
having the flexibility to prioritize
things like hey let's strategize hey
let's let's talk about stuff hey let's
spend some me and you time because you
know the rest of our life is being you
know dominated by this new parental
responsibility exactly so to bring that
around we don't we personally don't want
to trap ourselves into having to make as
much money as we're making so we always
are under spending for stuff because we
want to be able to take months and
months off to like slowly transition
into different things want and trying to
convert those large spikes of income
that come in with bug Bounty into longer
term passive income which is uh an area
that Mariah really excels in because she
can take that she has experience with
real estate investing and you know
getting that into various uh you know
passive cash flowing streams we make a
really good team too because I think I
do have a lot of vision and ideas and
desires and Justin is has a lot of I
like making that happen he's like super
skillful he loves to love me and so I'll
get a desire or an idea and it'll be
like three4 of the way baked and I'm
like hey Justin this is like a lot of
hard stuff can you like can we do this
and then he says yes and then we get
every you know we do what we want and
it's it's a really good look like moving
to Japan you know I had all the like the
groundwork and the vision and some of
the logistics but like I If I had had to
move to Japan to myself I would have had
to like be an English teacher and like
live on nothing and like all of these
things and with Justin the whole idea
was like the whole Vision was able to
change and we could make something way
better than my idea together yeah I
think I think we have a lot of you have
a lot of great vision for our our family
unit and then um I have a lot of follow
through and making it happen and uh
long-term follow through especially
long-term follow through and and I think
we also have various skills where um
they they overlap in a really or don't
overlap in a really positive way like a
lot of the supportive stuff that you
that you do I suck at cooking she she's
an amazing cook um and is very cognizant
of like oh it's time to eat Justin is
probably even though he doesn't know it
is low on energy you know and uh and
then you know me handling the paperwork
side of the real estate stuff you
handling the like hand
have to do the paperwork stuff most of
the time it works out really well I want
to Circle back around again I know we
got derailed to prizes and rewards for
your work so like even if you're not
doing a live hacking event you could do
this with your like monthly Inc comes a
little hard with bug boundy because it
really changes but maybe like three
Monon Clump income or something like
that would be a better way to do it if
you're not at the point where you're
going to live hacking events yeah like
definitely set yourself goals and reward
yourself you know and I kind of and it
was the way I was was raised too I kind
of thought that like buying yourself
stuff ever was like indulgent like we
always waited till Christmas to get
something that we wanted like we never
bought stuff we wanted like ever we just
didn't do it and my parents didn't and
we didn't and it didn't happen so I
thought it was like overindulgent to
just buy something that you wanted for
like 50 bucks 100 bucks I was like no
we're not we're not going to do that
right but like I really do feel like for
bug Bounty specifically it's an
investment in yourself in your like
motivation cuz motivation is the only
thing that's going to make money in bug
Bounty or like grind you can grind
through it you don't need motivation if
you're grinding but like you know you
want to keep yourself in a positive
cycle it's not a salary job it's not
sustainable if you're just grinding the
whole time yeah it's not a salary job so
you shouldn't treat your income like you
have a salaried income and be like Oh
50% goes to this bucket 20% goes to this
bucket at all times because it's
inherently has to be flexible but we
have different categories this is what
I've been trying to get back to we have
different categories of prizes and I
have it written down somewhere formally
if we ever to like release the formal
list but there's like just to help you
think of things that you can spend your
money on if you know unless you're
someone like ngi who has plenty of
things to spend money out on like that I
like that or Sam Curry or you know there
are lots of people who spend a lot of
money on a lot of
things but um if you're not if that
doesn't come naturally to you like it
didn't come naturally to me we
formalized buckets of fun spending money
cuz not everything is a toy for yourself
right there are like fun stuff that you
want for yourself that you don't need
right um and I think even within that
there's categories right like a new
video game system and video games is
like one thing but like maybe a hot tub
in a patio is like also a social
investment and also personal health
investment Home Improvement you know buy
yourself a physical trainer sorry don't
buy them buy their services right right
subscribe to a a physical trainer um
experiences is another one experience is
a huge one Vacations or classes like a
class on something that you're
interested in a dance class whatever um
gifts for other people like that you
know like Pro social gifts is a a whole
bucket of like people don't usually buy
their friend a car but if you get to the
financial point where you can buy
someone who needs a car a car do that
like do that as a pleasure spending for
yourself yeah exactly exactly like gift
yourself the gift of giving someone else
a car like that is an awesome bucket
right and that can be a goal for your
thing so it doesn't have to be you don't
have to buy yourself a hot tub you can
buy your dad a car you know like yeah
and and I think a lot of hackers do
spread that that money around which is
which is cool yeah wait well okay all
wrap it up because we you're we go we
got to get to this list here okay okay I
also want to say another like another
um category of like prize self- prize
but in a different like idea is is like
one is Investments like getting yourself
an investment you're excited about it
can also be a gift for yourself like you
can have a if I make this much money I
get to even like buy a single stock or
something right like something that
maybe you wouldn't have invested in
anyway like but you're excited to try
something spend you know 30% of your
thing on that and then the last one is
like just charitable is 30% an option I
didn't know if we were doing 30% we'll
talk about it for the next event who
knows maybe I'll do that uh charitable
gifts in general so instead of like a
pro-social gift like a gift to someone
you know and you can immediately receive
yeah like gratification back from you
can also like donate to a charity M like
I know maybe that sounds a little silly
to say but I feel like some people who
should really consider this just don't
consider it like helps with the tax
burden too because bugman is very tax
painful I would say we give away at
least 10 to 15% of our gross income not
even like our post- profit like we give
away a ton of money and that is awesome
like I love that for us I love that for
charity and individuals that we like
help out in life like pick a charity you
like pick a cause you like pick there
are like places you can donate that
spread out you know your gift to like
you know percent go here percent go here
you can pick a bulk chry whatever you
want to do like you can put good things
in the world with your money and it
doesn't all have to be for yourself
either so just throwing that out there
that's just my pitch is that is that
yeah that was like the last bucket I can
think of right now so another round of
applause here very good you one of the
things that I want to highlight here is
that clearly she's very passionate about
all of this right which I think is
really keeps energy up for us and I
think is is just an amazing blessing to
me to see to have her energized about
optimizing you know my career path and
my motivation and the the utilization of
the upsides of the path that we've
chosen um so I'm really grateful for
that and I think in general being proud
of yourself is better for you than
having an extra 10K laying around right
yeah of the lifestyle you're living of
yeah yeah of the lifestyle you're living
the choices you're making like be a
generous person make sure you're someone
you like even though you're like putting
all this effort in you're putting all
this work in like you're doing all this
learning like I know that it's a a grind
to do bug Bounty but like make sure at
the end of the day you are someone that
you like and if you're not make better
decisions you know I think that's very
doable
that yeah you guys can see why I am on
the path that I am on it's because of of
excellent WI from Mariah like this um we
do have to wrap it this one's getting a
little long but um I want to talk about
one last or I guess two last sections of
how to care for your hacker specifically
and how to care for your hacker wife so
what you know the majority of our
audience here is you know are the
technical are the are the bug Bounty
people right and uh how can um yeah
let's actually just jump to that second
one how can we let me sumarize the first
one real quick I think we talked about a
lot of stuff yeah we did I I spend a lot
of time trying to assist him because
financially and personally it makes a
lot of sense for me to assist his work
it's money efficient for me to not work
and help him work better so like foods
and stuff is what I do for him
definitely protect their space and time
and like brain power it's hacking is
really hard it's really cognitively hard
so like make sure you you just try to
give them space to do their thing and
like be there when they need to p and
tell them to suck it up they need that
and yeah just encourage them and like
you know just love them just be nice and
kind and patient as much as you can so I
love your voice when you said just love
them just love them um okay so how can
we as bug bounty hunters and people that
are spending so I think you know most of
the bug bounty hunters out there are are
doing this work after their work hours
right so it it it's it's uh it can feel
like a very work heavy environment right
how can we love our
our girlfriends and our spouses Etc um I
feel like there's there would be so many
different answers to like if it's a
girlfriend if it's a marriage partner if
it's a someone you have children with
right like I think there are lots of
obviously lots of think of balance in
life um my biggest one personally is
like if you say you are or are not going
to do something you must do or not do
that thing like if you say hey I'm going
to be off work by six o'clock
you be off work by six o'clock or or
before six o'clock have a a thorough
conversation with your spouse about that
5 5:30 if you're like really into
something and you know and in general I
try to be supportive too cuz like I like
it when we make money too right so it's
not always like a no you said six
o'clock but it is like hey if it's 6:15
and you said you're going to be off at 6
o'clock we haven't had a conversation
about
it that is always a bad move you cannot
do that to your spouse especially since
you are reiring so much flexibility of
them in general like we said like it is
okay to like need more time to work
sometimes but if you expect that without
communicating that you're going to tank
your whole relationship like that's
going to be such a bad such a bad look
yeah and I think one of the other things
that I've recently talked to another
hacker about is sort of this concept of
building up relational Equity before
there's about to be a drain so if I know
like hey there's about to be a live
hacking like let's go let's go on dates
let's you know really pour into the
relationship and get ourselves in like a
you know 10 out of 10 love bar fully
full yeah you know place before that
live hacking events even starts because
you know during that time period I am
juggling so many things I might make
some you know mistakes and hurt you and
and uh you know it's better to have that
that connection both both from like a
you supporting me perspective and for me
caring for you during this really
intense time um so I think that's
something we've also done pretty well
you know and I think just communicating
and maybe this is more of a you problem
than an everyone problem I think that
Justin sometimes doesn't notice what he
needs so he doesn't communicate what he
needs so like it took us two years to
just get to the point where we were like
oh he needs to be interrupted less when
he's working like that should not have
been like a two-year process right but
like recognize your in your try to try
to recognize in yourself what you do
need like what you do need in support
but if your partner is not on board for
you to be working every evening of week
hacking when you're working every day
and you have a kid like don't do that
[__] like just don't well yeah I mean
there's there's other alternatives to
that too I mean like you sleep later
than I do I wake up earlier right and so
if you need to flip that around from
evenings to mornings if it's really
important for you to get it done start
at 4 a.m or one of the one of the things
that I suggest as well is find a job
that is um project oriented so you know
have conversations with your boss I'm
not ever saying like you know this
behind your company's back or whatever
but um you know find a job where it's
like hey uh you complete this thing by
this time I don't care how how you do it
right I don't care what you what else
you do with your work time right and
then a lot of jobs are like and then get
really good at your job and free up some
time and then use that time to do bug
Bounty I think that's a great I think
that's a great framework like if it's
important enough for you to want to
override what your partner wants right
like if it's that important to you then
then make your own time for it like make
the 5:00 a.m. to 9:00 a.m. time before
you have to go to work 4 hours is a ton
of time and it's really inconvenient but
it's much better than sucking that time
away from your partner in the evening if
that's become a conflict in your
relationship or find some compromise
right some compromise where where
there's some nights per week that you're
hacking and sometimes you know but then
if you're doing it like that especially
if you're like already hitting conflict
with your partner you just it's it
really is a lot to ask to have you know
a hobby that's so brain consuming so
time consuming right this isn't like a
cute video game you can pause and like
take a 30 minute break and then like go
back to what you were doing right it is
it's it takes a lot of you away so I
would just be really respectful about it
and yeah I think the more you have in
play is like a marriage partner is
different than a girlfriend and a
someone you have kids with is different
than a marriage just a marriage partner
too like the more you have in play the
more complicated it becomes and all
right so now it's my turn to to dig on
you a little bit here so um so well one
of the things I had on the list here
that we have concreted um and I think we
do pretty well on now is the concept of
me giving you my eyes when you do have
conversations with me right so you know
she she tries to um reduce the amount of
times that you know that you're
interrupting right and and when when you
do come in the room I try to I try to
give you my eyes right away now I'm not
I'm not staring at my computer being
like mhm yep yeah yeah can you can
schedule that for Friday you know like
like a comp we had for the first couple
yeah is is you know if she's giving me
that that extra respect of you know
holding off and and that sort of thing
then I when she does come into the room
I give her my full attention and we we
talk and we are efficient about it and
then there's also just a level of
connection there as well of like you
know I know that it's a big thing for
you to feel love uh that I'm looking at
your eyes and I've given you my full
attention right um actually it's funny
before this podcast I was like oh you
know I hope we finish up the podcast in
a good amount of time then we can go you
know get coffee and stuff like that and
she was like well you're going to be
like staring at me the whole time and
talking to me so this is kind of like a
date already it is kind of like a date
it is kind of like a date um and so uh I
think I think that's probably more
generally applicable I know that you get
a little extra out of the the eye
contact thing but I think that's
probably generally applicable as well um
I also want to add like back to the
girlfriend supporting your partners you
know if there is conflict you know maybe
you've compromised you say like all
right half the half the days a week or
half the evenings a week you can like
take the whole evening and hack and I'll
just do whatever else right I think our
I don't know if it's our generation or
day and time and space right I think
it's really easy to be really dependent
on your partner for most of your like
social and mental needs and I think you
know there's a lot there's good stuff in
that but I think it's so important if
your partner is a hacker and all of
their attention is on this thing you've
got to get Hobbies you know like you
have to have stuff in your life life you
can't just watch TV every night that
they're doing something that's really
interesting and engaging to them one
it's going to make you a worse partner
if you just sit there doing nothing and
two you're going to be so much less
happy like get a hobby get six Hobbies
like get one for every night of the week
get six Hobbies get a book club get
something you like doing by yourself get
like a standing coffee date like you
don't have to sit home miserable all the
time either cough cough play League of
Legends League of Legends that's a great
one um don't just let yourself be bored
and like waiting for your spouse to be
done with the thing that they really
like doing that's a for dis that's a
disservice to both people in the
relationship I agree all right we are we
are an hour hour and a half in it looks
like and uh I I don't have anything else
I don't think uh on my list so Mariah
thank you for stepping in today and I
love you so much and uh that was a great
podcast and that's a wrap on this
episode of critical thinking thanks so
much for listening and if you want more
critical thinking content head over to
ctbb show/ Discord join the Discord
there's lot of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes amas hack
alongs exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you there
[Music]